<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Specual</title>
    <link>https://specual.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Specual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© Frecklemaid</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://specual.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/about/</guid>
      <description>At just 21 years old I have accomplished an overwhelming amount of nothing, so if this blog brightens even one persons day I&amp;rsquo;d be stoked. In my normal, not-on-the-internet life I frequent my university where I&amp;rsquo;m studying a double degree in Arts and IT. I spend way too little time doing coursework, so writing random blog posts provides an entertaining way to procrastinate, and given the Coronapocalypse that&amp;rsquo;s going on as I&amp;rsquo;m writing this it&amp;rsquo;s also providing a useful distraction from the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Currently Reading: June 2023</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/cr23-06-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/cr23-06-03/</guid>
      <description>This month I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling to Israel, Egypt and Greece before jetting off to Thailand at the end of the month. This means that I may not have a ton of time for reading depending on how long I&amp;rsquo;ll be out each day and able to stand the sweltering heat. However, I am currently in the middle of a few books. My general goals with reading this year centred around language learning - namely Spanish and French.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Time of Changes by Robert Silverberg</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/timeofchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/timeofchanges/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;A Time of Changes&amp;rsquo; by Robert Silverberg puts us in the mind of Kinnal Darival, a middle-aged exiled Prince as he&amp;rsquo;s pursued across a punishing desert for his counter-cultural transformation. In Borthan, no greater a verbal crime exists than that of &amp;lsquo;self-baring&amp;rsquo;. Like a high-school history essay, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo; are illegal according to the Covenant of the world&amp;rsquo;s colonisation, and citizens must speak in verbose roundabouts to avoid too great a focus on their own existence or feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are simplified language texts worth reading in language learning? - Western Philsophy in Simple Spanish by Olly Richards</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/westernphilosophyinspanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/westernphilosophyinspanish/</guid>
      <description>In my quest to learn Spanish, and my continued attempts to maintain my French, have led me to the &amp;lsquo;input method&amp;rsquo; of language learning. According to this, the primary thing which determines a language learners command of the language is the amount of comprehensible, high-quality input which they get. Naturally, it can be very difficult when first starting a language to understand anything, let alone native-level media on subjects that you&amp;rsquo;d be interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Chessboard of 1997; Or, The World According to America</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/thegrandchessboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/thegrandchessboard/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzeziński explores the world according to America (at least, in 1997.) Brzeziński was a Polish-born political analyst with no shortage of high-profile roles on his resume, serving as a counsellor to Johnson from &amp;lsquo;66-68 and National Security Advisor from &amp;lsquo;77-81 under Carter. The Grand Chessboard presents Brzeziński&amp;rsquo;s own geopolitical analysis of the world and its various key &amp;lsquo;pieces&amp;rsquo; to the American Imperial puzzle. Thus, it particularly focuses on Europe (particularly France and Germany), Russia, the Caucasus, and China in their geopolitical contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ogres by Adrian Tchaikovsky - Suprisingly political?</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/ogres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/ogres/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Ogres&amp;rsquo; is a novella by sci-fi and fantasy megalith, Adrian Tchaikovsky. The world juxtaposes normal, common humanity with the ruling Ogre class. Larger than everyone else, the ogres rule by inherent genetic &amp;lsquo;supremacy&amp;rsquo; in a feudal-esque steampunk setting. After killing his feudal landlords son, Torquell, larger and stronger than most other humans, is on the run. Eventually his time in imprisonment and servitude sees him discover a chilling truth about the nature of the world, and the origin of the ogres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if Hitler had written sci-fi? - The Iron Dream by Norman Spinrad</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/theirondream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/theirondream/</guid>
      <description>In 1972 Nebula Award nominee &amp;lsquo;The Iron Dream&amp;rsquo;, Norman Spinrad asks the question: What if Hitler had written a science fiction novel? The Iron Dream thus forms a novel within a novel, as beside an introduction and afterword, the reader is thrust into &amp;lsquo;The Lord of the Swastika&amp;rsquo;, Hitler&amp;rsquo;s most famous science fiction work. The Lord of the Swastika presents a homoerotic tale of world domination where the true human genotype is restored to primacy in a post-apocalyptic Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens when you stop loving YA?</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/endingya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/endingya/</guid>
      <description>For many of us who have grown up to be voracious readers, the Young Adult literary space is a reliable and familiar home. On choosing a YA book, you are somewhat guaranteed to encounter simple prose and young, often female main characters in ‘coming-of-age’ stories. Young Adult is not restricted by genres like science fiction or romance, and it is a perfectly valid place to stay if you’re happy there. But what do you do, if like me, young adult starts to wear thin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://specual.me/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
