<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nonfiction on Specual</title>
    <link>https://specual.me/tags/nonfiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nonfiction on Specual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© Frecklemaid</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://specual.me/tags/nonfiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Currently Reading: June 2023</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/cr23-06-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/cr23-06-03/</guid>
      <description>This month I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling to Israel, Egypt and Greece before jetting off to Thailand at the end of the month. This means that I may not have a ton of time for reading depending on how long I&amp;rsquo;ll be out each day and able to stand the sweltering heat. However, I am currently in the middle of a few books. My general goals with reading this year centred around language learning - namely Spanish and French.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are simplified language texts worth reading in language learning? - Western Philsophy in Simple Spanish by Olly Richards</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/westernphilosophyinspanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/westernphilosophyinspanish/</guid>
      <description>In my quest to learn Spanish, and my continued attempts to maintain my French, have led me to the &amp;lsquo;input method&amp;rsquo; of language learning. According to this, the primary thing which determines a language learners command of the language is the amount of comprehensible, high-quality input which they get. Naturally, it can be very difficult when first starting a language to understand anything, let alone native-level media on subjects that you&amp;rsquo;d be interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Chessboard of 1997; Or, The World According to America</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/thegrandchessboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/thegrandchessboard/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzeziński explores the world according to America (at least, in 1997.) Brzeziński was a Polish-born political analyst with no shortage of high-profile roles on his resume, serving as a counsellor to Johnson from &amp;lsquo;66-68 and National Security Advisor from &amp;lsquo;77-81 under Carter. The Grand Chessboard presents Brzeziński&amp;rsquo;s own geopolitical analysis of the world and its various key &amp;lsquo;pieces&amp;rsquo; to the American Imperial puzzle. Thus, it particularly focuses on Europe (particularly France and Germany), Russia, the Caucasus, and China in their geopolitical contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
