<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Specual</title>
    <link>https://specual.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Specual</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>Page(/posts)</language>
    <managingEditor>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© Frecklemaid</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://specual.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>L’Âge des low-tech by Philippe Bihouix</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/bihouix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/bihouix/</guid>
      <description>‘L’Âge des Low-Tech’ or ‘The Age of Low Tech’ by Philippe Bihouix asks the question: Can we out-think our consumption of resources? According to Bihouix, the answer is a resounding no. No amount of technological innovation will be able to support the technologically complex lifestyles we now prefer. In the face of anthropogenic environmental impacts, Bihouix posits that our prime solution lies not in technological innovations which shift to alternate environmental impacts, but in the technical simplifcation of our societies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Harlem Renaissance, Edited by Cary D. Wintz</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/harlemrenaissance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/harlemrenaissance/</guid>
      <description>‘The Harlem Renaissance’ provides a keen look into the interwar African-American literary movement after which it is titled. Wintz provides both a history and anthology of key pieces from the movement in his efforts to provide a comprehensive overview of the historical key authors and themes. I will attempt in this review to address primarily the efforts of Wintz and not the writers which he included in the anthology that made up the bulk of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elle et son chat by Makoto Shinkai (trans. Naruki Nakagawa)</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/elleetsonchat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/elleetsonchat/</guid>
      <description>‘Elle et son chat’ by Makoto Shinkai is a collection of interconnected stories about the cats of a neighbourhood in Tokyo. Throughout we get to see the perspective of the cats and their people. A perfect airport book purchase, I read this across a week of travel and had a wonderful time.
Cozy, Wholesome Vibes This book is rife with wholesome but at times sad vibes. The author doesn’t shy away from topics of mental health including loneliness, agoraphobia, sexual assault and loss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Judaism: A Very Short Introduction by Norman Solomon</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/judaismvsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/judaismvsi/</guid>
      <description>A part of the Oxford ‘A Very Short Introduction’ series, ‘Judaism’ by Norman Solomon aims to introduce key concepts of Judaism and Jewish history to the gentile reader. The book covers various aspects of Judaism and Jewish history in a fairly informal ‘question and answer’ style. The sections of the book include key faith concepts, the split between Christianity and Judaism, history of sacred texts, celebrations, spiritual practice, Zionism, persecution and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin Stories by Robert Walser</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/berlinstories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/berlinstories/</guid>
      <description>If at any time you find yourself enamoured by the thrum of a metropolis, by Melbourne, Rome, Manchester or any other suitably sized place, ‘Berlin Stories’ will put words to the possibility you feel pulsing there. Robert Walser, in his signature ‘prose pieces’ – a combination of poetic prose and essay – perfectly encapsulates what is so invigorating about a city. Masterfully selected, the ‘Berlin Stories’ collection edited by Susan Bernovsky traverses Walser’s time in Berlin: from joyful youth to the still joyful but matured man who eventually returned to his Swiss origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Currently Reading: June 2023</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/cr23-06-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/cr23-06-03/</guid>
      <description>This month I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling to Israel, Egypt and Greece before jetting off to Thailand at the end of the month. This means that I may not have a ton of time for reading depending on how long I&amp;rsquo;ll be out each day and able to stand the sweltering heat. However, I am currently in the middle of a few books. My general goals with reading this year centred around language learning - namely Spanish and French.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Time of Changes by Robert Silverberg</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/timeofchanges/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/timeofchanges/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;A Time of Changes&amp;rsquo; by Robert Silverberg puts us in the mind of Kinnal Darival, a middle-aged exiled Prince as he&amp;rsquo;s pursued across a punishing desert for his counter-cultural transformation. In Borthan, no greater a verbal crime exists than that of &amp;lsquo;self-baring&amp;rsquo;. Like a high-school history essay, &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;me&amp;rsquo; are illegal according to the Covenant of the world&amp;rsquo;s colonisation, and citizens must speak in verbose roundabouts to avoid too great a focus on their own existence or feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are simplified language texts worth reading in language learning? - Western Philsophy in Simple Spanish by Olly Richards</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/westernphilosophyinspanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/westernphilosophyinspanish/</guid>
      <description>In my quest to learn Spanish, and my continued attempts to maintain my French, have led me to the &amp;lsquo;input method&amp;rsquo; of language learning. According to this, the primary thing which determines a language learners command of the language is the amount of comprehensible, high-quality input which they get. Naturally, it can be very difficult when first starting a language to understand anything, let alone native-level media on subjects that you&amp;rsquo;d be interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand Chessboard of 1997; Or, The World According to America</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/thegrandchessboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/thegrandchessboard/</guid>
      <description>The Grand Chessboard by Zbigniew Brzeziński explores the world according to America (at least, in 1997.) Brzeziński was a Polish-born political analyst with no shortage of high-profile roles on his resume, serving as a counsellor to Johnson from &amp;lsquo;66-68 and National Security Advisor from &amp;lsquo;77-81 under Carter. The Grand Chessboard presents Brzeziński&amp;rsquo;s own geopolitical analysis of the world and its various key &amp;lsquo;pieces&amp;rsquo; to the American Imperial puzzle. Thus, it particularly focuses on Europe (particularly France and Germany), Russia, the Caucasus, and China in their geopolitical contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ogres by Adrian Tchaikovsky - Suprisingly political?</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/ogres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/ogres/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Ogres&amp;rsquo; is a novella by sci-fi and fantasy megalith, Adrian Tchaikovsky. The world juxtaposes normal, common humanity with the ruling Ogre class. Larger than everyone else, the ogres rule by inherent genetic &amp;lsquo;supremacy&amp;rsquo; in a feudal-esque steampunk setting. After killing his feudal landlords son, Torquell, larger and stronger than most other humans, is on the run. Eventually his time in imprisonment and servitude sees him discover a chilling truth about the nature of the world, and the origin of the ogres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if Hitler had written sci-fi? - The Iron Dream by Norman Spinrad</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/theirondream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/theirondream/</guid>
      <description>In 1972 Nebula Award nominee &amp;lsquo;The Iron Dream&amp;rsquo;, Norman Spinrad asks the question: What if Hitler had written a science fiction novel? The Iron Dream thus forms a novel within a novel, as beside an introduction and afterword, the reader is thrust into &amp;lsquo;The Lord of the Swastika&amp;rsquo;, Hitler&amp;rsquo;s most famous science fiction work. The Lord of the Swastika presents a homoerotic tale of world domination where the true human genotype is restored to primacy in a post-apocalyptic Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happens when you stop loving YA?</title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/endingya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/endingya/</guid>
      <description>For many of us who have grown up to be voracious readers, the Young Adult literary space is a reliable and familiar home. On choosing a YA book, you are somewhat guaranteed to encounter simple prose and young, often female main characters in ‘coming-of-age’ stories. Young Adult is not restricted by genres like science fiction or romance, and it is a perfectly valid place to stay if you’re happy there. But what do you do, if like me, young adult starts to wear thin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://specual.me/posts/athens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>fqaouwsst@mozmail.com (Mackenzie Fletcher)</author>
      <guid>https://specual.me/posts/athens/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>